维吉妮亚  维吉妮亚  维吉妮亚
Virginia? Virginia? Virginia?
猜我是怎么弄到这个的
Guess how I got this.
我最爱玩这个了
Ooh, I love this game!
"猜我是怎么弄到这个的"游戏
"Guess how I got this" Was a game
我爹妈已经乐此不疲好多年了
my parents hadbeen playing for years.
猜我是怎么弄到这个的
Guess how I got this.
我不想吹牛
I don't want to brag,
但我差不多算是这个游戏的灵感之源
but I was sort of the inspiration for this game.
猜我是怎么弄到这个的
Guess how I got this.
我猜莎拉・麦劳克兰
I'm gonna guess that Sarah McLachlan
又把海鲜市场的所有龙虾都放生了
freed all the lobsters from the Seafood Shack again.
不对
Nope.
你和缅因州的州长打赌赢了
You won a bet with the governor of Maine.
塞布丽娜  大街上才没有州长呢
Sabrina, Main Street doesn't have a governor.
吉米把缅因州误听成大街
说话前动动脑子好吗
You got to think before you guess.
你们把这游戏的乐趣都毁了
You know, you guys are ruining this game.
你从哪儿弄到这龙虾的  伯特
Where'd you get the lobster, Burt?
泰勒付不起我整理草坪的钱
Tyler couldn't pay me for mowing his lawn,
就把这小家伙抵给我了
so he gave me this little fella.
-伯特  我觉得你占到大便宜了呢  -是啊
- Burt, I think you got the better end of that deal. - Yeah.
超市的龙虾我们可买不起呢
We could never afford lobsters at the store.
是啊  泰勒说超市必须高价出售
I know! Tyler says supermarkets have to overcharge
因为有层层的中间人都要收取费用
because of all the middlemen they have to pay.
送货的  送冰的
The delivery guy, the ice guy,
那些没用的装袋工和收银员
those useless baggers and checkers.
我讨厌他们
Oh, I hate those guys.
吉米  我们就是干那行的
Jimmy, we are those guys.
你应该跟泰勒说好以后都用龙虾结账
You should make this a regular thing with Tyler.
正有此意
I'm gonna.
但我在想  怎能满足于区区一只龙虾呢
But I was thinking, why stop with lobster?
这玩意完全可以做大啊
This could be huge.
想想其他可以交换的东西
Think of the other things I could trade for.
螃蟹  虾  各种贝类
Crabs, shrimp, mollusks.
别停  再往大处想
No. Think bigger.
还有啊  牡蛎吗
I don't know. Oysters.
鹈鹕
Um, uh... pelicans!
再大点
Even bigger.
我们可以一起用自己的服务来换实物
We could both trade services for stuff.
我们的工作量一点没加
We'd be doing the same amount of work,
但回报更丰厚
but enjoying a much bigger return on the cool stuff.
听起来不错啊
That sounds great!
你们也可以找些可以交换的技能加入我们
You guys should find some tradable skills and join us.
你们总该有什么擅长的吧
Must be something you're good at.
我特别擅长避免把自己扯进荒诞的事里
I've gotten really good at avoiding ridiculous ideas,
所以别算上我们
which is why we're gonna bow out.
再说  明天巴尼要给我们上急救课
Plus, we have Barney's first aid class tomorrow.
急救课  你学那个干啥
First aid class? What do you need that for?
急救只是那些卖纱布的捏造的骗局
First aid is just a scam dreamed up by the gauze and bandage people.
或者它就是个行之有效的救命措施
Or a proven life saver.
是啊  喜旺大部分时间都你们带
Yeah, and since Hope spends so much time here,
所以我们希望你们也能去听听课
we think you guys ought to check out the class, too,
就当是为了喜旺
for Hope's sake.
吉米  孩子难免受伤
Jimmy, kids get hurt--
擦伤手肘  割到手指
they scrape their elbows, they cut their finger,
从车底的洞里掉下去
they fall through a hole in the bottom of your car.
这都是无法避免的
Nothing you can do to avoid it.
再说我们这里有个超级完美的急救箱
Besides, we got a perfectly good first aid kit right here.
瞧
See?
"发射求救信号  吃个三明治  等待救援"
"Shoot flare, eat sandwich, wait for help."
我也不知道  或许他们说的对
I don't know. Maybe they're right.
不如我们直接翘掉培训课吧
Maybe we should just skip the class and...
吉米
Jimmy.
天啊
Oh, my.
时间真是把杀猪刀
Oh, the years have not been kind
火鸡色拉三明治变毒药
to this turkey salad sandwich.
第二天  我父母把以物换物计划付诸实践
The next day, my parents put their bartering plan into action,
竟然还成功了
and it actually worked.
他们得到了需要的
They got things they needed.
和不需要的东西
They got things they didn't need.
也享受了早就该去做的事
And they got things that were long overdue.
冲洗
Rinse.
最重要的是  他们得到了一直以来长期梦寐以求的东西
Most importantly, they got things they had always dreamt about.
我们这儿有如此美味的枫糖浆
Oh, if we have maple syrup this incredible here,
何必还要舔着脸找加拿大进口
why do we even talk to Canada?
天啊
Oh, man.
巴布  你的高超手法让我
Barb, what you're doing right now is actually
十分乐意帮你清理下水槽口蓄积的毛发
making me look forward to cleaning your drain hair.
维吉妮亚  瞧瞧我的新帽子
Hey, Virginia, check out my new lid.
我替斯蒂芬老太太清洗泳池  她帮我做的
Old Lady Stevens made this for me for cleaning out her pool.
以物换物真是有史以来最棒的事
This bartering thing-- it's the greatest thing ever.
没错  按摩  龙虾  毛线帽
I know. Massages, lobsters, crocheted hats.
我们简直是以物换物的大师
It's like we're barter-aires!
我在想
I was thinking.
如果那些和我们交换的人
what if the people who are trading with us
相互间也进行同样的交易呢
started trading with each other?
是啊  对整个纳什维尔而言
Yeah. Natesville would become a place
生命中那些美好的事
where the good things in life
可以向那些一直辛苦劳作的人倾斜
actually trickle up to the people who do all the work.
倾斜式经济
A trickle-up economy.
我觉得真有那玩意儿呢
I think that's a thing.
不是
No.
我突然想起挠痒娃娃了[与倾斜式经济谐音]
I'm thinking Tickle Me Elmo.
你们或许都很好奇我为何有资格教这堂课
You all may wonder why I'm qualified to teach this class.
我童子军时期可学到过不少东西
Well, I learned a thing or two from the trusty scouts.
他们把我打个半死之后
They would often administer first aid
总是会对我采取急救措施
after they beat the tarnation out of me.
可能因为我是一个特别容易搞定的家伙
I suppose I was an easy target.
超重  气喘  贫血
Overweight, asthmatic, anemic
还是个重度色盲
and wildly color blind.
怎么迟到了  没事吧
You're late. Is everything all right?
我刚收到我妈寄来的明信片
I just got this postcard from my mother.
"真希望你也在这儿"
"Wish You Were Here."
-她这次挺和善的  -想太多  看背面
- Oh, she's being nice this time. - Yeah. Turn it over.
"因为在厄瓜尔多做前额缩小术超级便宜
"Because forehead reduction surgery is super cheap in Ecuador.
爱你  塔玛"
Love, Tams."
别难过  亲爱的
Oh, I'm sorry, sweetie.
不  我该感到荣幸才对
Yeah. Really, I should be flattered.
她虽然身在热带天堂
I mean, even in tropical paradise,
心里却还在想着我的缺点
she's thinking about my flaws.
不幸的是  我被胖揍了六顿
Unfortunately, I took six brutal beatings
才知道根本没有什么残忍勋章
before I learned there was no merit badge for cruelty,
而那些童子军对我施暴时我竟然不做反抗
and I'd been letting the scouts pummel me for no real reason.
大家好
Hey, everybody.
瞧瞧我的大奶罐
Check out my big cans.
还记得乔希吗  他走了几年又回来了
You all remember Josh. He's back after a couple years away.
第六号海豹突击队
SEAL Team Six.
乔希很擅长拿杂货开玩笑
Josh is amazing with grocery humor.
他曾用水壶开过一个类似的玩笑
He does a similar joke with jugs.
当我爸妈把纳什维尔的所有技工都召集齐了后
Once my parents had gathered all of Natesville's skilled workers,
他们打算将计划付诸实施
they attempted to lay out the plan.
但有些人花了好些时间才明白
It took a while for some of them to understand.
大家好  我是酒鬼菲尔
Hi. My name's Phil, and I'm an alcoholic.
你好  菲尔
Hi, Phil.
菲尔  我再说一遍
Phil, for the second time,
这里不是互助会
that's not why we're here.
在过去的几天里
Oh. For the past few days,
维吉妮亚和我过上了一种
Virginia and I have enjoyed a lifestyle
曾经我们无法企及的生活方式
that previously was beyond our reach.
我们怎么办到的  伯特
How did we do it, Burt?
通过以物换物
Through barter. Oh.
事实是  我仅仅修了几个小时的草坪
In fact, after only a few hours of lawn work,
就可以交换到一个
I was able to trade for something that was heretofore
迄今为止只有富豪跟海象可以享用的东西
only available to tycoons and walruses.
是什么呢
What is it?
好吧  答案就在你们的椅子下
Well, look under your chairs and find out!
这不是龙虾吗
Is that a lobster?
正是
That's right.
龙虾归你了
You get a lobster!
快把龙虾带回家吧
你也得到了一只龙虾
You get a lobster!
痛
No!
帮我弄掉它
Make it stop!
抱歉我只能用纸巾
Sorry about the paper towel.
因为我不相信纱布
I don't believe in gauze.
我们想说的是
The thing we're trying to say is,
之所以我能交换到这么多龙虾
I was able to trade for all these lobsters
是因为我们跳过了中间商
because we cut out the middleman.
我不用付钱给送货的
I didn't have to pay the delivery guy,
也不用付钱给在龙虾鳌上套橡胶圈的
or the claw-rubberbanderer guy.
真心对不住 巴布
Sorry again, Barb.
我们正邀请你们做一样的事情
And we're inviting you to do the same thing,
不仅仅是跟我们  是跟大家所有人
and not just with us, but with each other.
因为越多的人参与其中
Because the more people that are involved,
越多人获利
the more people benefit.
再提醒一下  这不是在搞"金字塔骗局"
And again, this is not a pyramid scheme.
金字塔骗局也称层压式推销  即以根本不可能支付的高利息作诱饵进行金融诈骗
就算你是干这行的
Although if you make pyramids,
我们一样欢迎你入局
you're welcome to join our scheme.
我是说加入体系
Uh, I mean, system.
那你的意思是
So, are you saying
我可以用龙虾跟史蒂文斯老太太
I can trade Old Lady Stevens lobsters
换一套42码的修身针织套装
for a crocheted suit in a 42 slim?
噢  孩子  这肯定行不通
Oh, honey, that's not gonna work.
我对龙虾过敏的
I'm allergic to crustaceans.
这很简单
That's easy.
我替你修草坪
I mow your lawn,
你给泰勒针织套装
you give Tyler the suit,
泰勒给我龙虾
Tyler gives me the lobsters.
另外
Again,
我再强调一遍
I can't stress enough,
这不是"金字塔骗局"
this is not a pyramid scheme.
克拉拉・巴顿表示同意
And Clara Barton said, "You know what? I will."
克拉拉・巴顿  美国红十字会创始人
我想这基本上概述了急救的起源
And that, I think, covers the origins of first aid.
噢  我没想到居然花了1小时45分钟
Oh, I can't believe that took an hour and 45 minutes.
好吧  我们接着说窒息
Oh, well, let's move quickly to choking.
这些都是最常见的容易噎到的东西
Now, here are the most common choking hazards.
总算有吃的了  我饿了
Finally, some food. I'm starving.
吉米  吉米  吉米
Jimmy? Jimmy? Jimmy?
我想吉米真的噎到了
I think James is really choking!
大家不要慌
Okay, nobody panic.
有人真的用过海姆利克氏操作法吗
Has anyone here ever actually done the Heimlich?
我
Yes.
人家只在人形枕头上实施过呀
I've only ever done it with my special body pillow.
没用  我的手好滑
Oh, it's no use. My hands are slipping!
都怪我擦手霜的强迫症
Damn my vain compulsion to moisturize!
我的手很漂亮  但毫无用处
My hands are beautiful, but useless!
我的天  吉米的老婆
Oh, my God. Jimmy's wife
刚刚救了吉米
just saved his life.
太弱了吧
What a wuss!
吉米  接下来呢
Hey, Jimmy, what's next?
你要坐下来小便吗
Are you gonna start peeing sitting down?
你可以闭嘴了吗 乔希
Okay, you know what? Can you just cut it out, Josh?
好  好  冷静点
Okay, okay, calm down.
这又弄不死他 只是玩笑而已
They're not gonna kill him. They're jokes,
又不是葡萄
not grapes.
对不起  吉米
I apologize, Jimmy.
如果我不跟着笑
If I don't laugh along with his jokes,
他就改取笑我了
he'll start making fun of me again.
你懂的  我浑身上下确实充满了笑点
As you know, I'm a veritable minefield of mockable traits.
没事的  弗兰克
It's all right, Frank.
弗兰克  你来吗
Yo, Frank, you coming?
马上  我在给吉米指卫生巾的位置
Yeah. I was just pointing Jimmy towards the sanitary napkins.
真的很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
你没事吧
Hey, are you okay?
我又不是个小孩  塞布丽娜
Hey, you know, I'm not a baby, Sabrina, all right?
我能照顾好我自己
I-I can take care of myself.
这算什么啊
What was that all about?
你救了他的命
I'm afraid you saved his life,
同时也可能扼杀了他的男子气概
but in the process, you may have killed his manhood.
他被噎到了
Well, he was choking.
我还能怎么办
What was I supposed to do?
你也可以等专业人士出现
Well, you could have waited for the professionals to show up.
又不是说牺牲一些脑细胞
It's not like a few less brain cells
会让他少得一个普利策奖
is gonna cost him a Pulitzer.
好吧  那我下次就看着他在大伙面前噎到
Oh, okay, so, I should just wait for him
不去救他咯
to choke in public again, and then not save him?
那可得过段时间了
Oh, that could take days,
但我觉得他撑不到那时候
and I don't think he's got that kind of time.
你得帮他把他的男子气概找回来
You've got to help him get his masculinity back.
我该怎么帮
How am I supposed to do that?
你问我干嘛
Why are you asking me?
我有两个妈妈  没有老婆
I have two mothers, no wife,
而且曾经狂殴我的童子军还都是妹子
and those scouts who used to beat me up... were girls.
我们有麻烦了  伯特
We've got a problem, Burt.
我给了巴布一只龙虾  但她只帮我
I gave Barb a lobster, but she only massaged
按摩左半边的身体
the left side of my body.
我尝一口就知道自己根本不爱吃龙虾
It only took me one to realize I don't really like lobster.
我只喜欢溶化的黄油
Turns out, I just really like melted butter.
但现在我的左半边很爽
But now my left side is relaxed,
而右半边的肌肉却紧得难受
and my right side is tense as hell.
好吧  我们想想怎么办
Okay, we can figure this out.
伯特  看看这个
Burt, look at this.
我明白
I totally get it.
你是一个套着备用轮胎的技工
You're a mechanic with a spare tire.
很明显  现在一瓶油
Apparently, an oil change
只够换半件毛衣
is only worth half a sweater now.
织毛衣很花时间的
Knitting a sweater takes a long time.
你最好庆幸它可以盖得到你的胸部
Just be happy it covers your man boobs.
至少它们没有下垂到我的膝盖
At least they're not bouncing off my knees,
你这个没用的老太婆
you useless bag of wrinkles.
我们能解决这些问题的
We can work this out.
首先  菲尔  跟你妈道歉
First, Phil, apologize to your mother.
不幸的是  越来越多人
Unfortunately, there were more than a few people
在爸爸妈妈的计划上出了状况
that had a problem with Mom and Dad's plan.
所以他们聚集所有人
So they brought everyone together
来解决他们的问题
and tried to figure things out.
如果泰勒给了巴布两只龙虾
Okay, so if Tyler gives two lobsters to Barb,
巴布给康威医生做三分之一疗程的按摩
and Barb gives a third of a massage to Dr. Conway,
然后康威医生再为预言家帕姆
and Dr. Conway cleans four of Pam,
洗四颗牙
the fortune teller's teeth...
没错  然后帕姆
Right, and she gives half
再告诉菲尔下周彩票号码的一半
of next week's lottery numbers to Phil,
菲尔去为糖浆山姆修车
Phil fixes Syrup Sam's truck
以交换六块煎饼
in exchange for six pancakes
等值于山姆给史蒂文斯老太太的枫糖浆
worth of syrup to Old Lady Stevens.
而老太太要织帽子给...
Who makes a crocheted hat for...
等等  谁要针织帽子来着
Wait. Who needs a crocheted hat?
我们的微经济组织可能遭遇了"帽子泡沫"
Our micro economic group may be experiencing a Hat Bubble.
也许我们不需要等价交换
Maybe we don't have to trade
某种特定的服务
one particular service for another?
或许我们可以创造某种东西
Maybe there's something we can create
来代表服务的价值
that represents the value of services rendered.
比如彩色珠子  或者纸
Like colored beads or a piece of paper.
纸这个想法很高端
Paper's a good idea.
很新颖
That's pretty cool.
但如果要显得官方正式
But to make it even more official...
我们就该在上面加个头像
we should put someone's face on it!
加谁的头像呢
Now, who could that be?
为了让这个以物换物系统更高级
To bring their barter system to the next level,
爹妈去了李的复印店
my parents went down to Lee's Copy Shop
让李印刷了几百张伯特币
and had him print up hundreds of Burt Bucks.
这些足够流通了
There's plenty to go around.
相信我  有了这个  一切就简单多了
Trust me, this'll make everything easier.
币值有三元  七元和十一元
They come in threes, sevens and 11's.
这都是伯特的幸运数字
Those are Burt's lucky numbers.
回击乔希的羞辱
去死吧
你饭做得有吉米好吗
你骂我的话都会应在你自己身上
不
No...
你才是呢
you are.
太棒了
Oh, that's good.
吉米  吉米  救命啊
Jimmy! Jimmy, help!
我来救你了
Oh! I'll get you!
天啊
Oh, my god!
弗兰克  停下
Hey, Frank! Stop!
Frank! Stop!
天啊
Oh, my god.
经典啊
Ha! Classic!
恭喜啊  吉米
Congratulations, Jimmy.
你马上就要从
You're about to go from being
本超市最大傻瓜
the biggest idiot in the store
荣升至全网最大傻瓜了
to the biggest on the Internet.
不  你才是呢
No, you are!
干得好  詹姆斯  你是个英雄
Well done, James. You're a hero.
如果你没有抓住吊在空中的塞布丽娜
If you hadn't caught the dangling Sabrina,
她可能会摔断"嘴"
she may have... broken a log.
不对头啊
Wait, that doesn't make any sense.
是腿
Oh. A leg.
甚至...
Or...
可能断头
cut off her head?
等等
Wait a minute.
这都是你们演的吗
You guys faked this?
想必她要伪造的还不止这些吧
Bet that's not the only thing she has to fake.
抱歉  我以为乔希还在呢
Sorry, I thought Josh was still here.
我要去做手指甲和脚趾甲啦
Well, I'm off to my mani-pedi.
能借我一点伯特币吗
Can you spot me a few Burt bucks?
不行啊  我最后一点也全花在
No. I spent my last ones on a crochet lesson
斯蒂芬老太太的针织课上了
from Old Lady Stevens,
这样我就能给马桶织个舒服的垫子了
so I can make this toilet seat cozy.
冬天的时候肯定很爽
that's gonna be great in winter,
如果你没有伯特币了
but if you're out of Burt Bucks
我也没有伯特币了  那就麻烦了
and I'm out of Burt Bucks, then we got a problem.
那你就得修剪更多的草坪
I guess you're just gonna have to mow more lawns
我也不得不去给更多人家干活
and I'm gonna have to clean more houses.
可我今天想去修手修脚啊
But my mani-pedi's today.
我的手裁伯特币裁得好辛苦
I've got so many paper cuts from handling all those Burt Bucks,
我要给手打蜡呢
I'm getting a hot paraffin wax dip.
绝不能错过了  维吉妮亚  不能
I can't miss that, Virginia, I just can't.
太不公平了  如果说这世上有谁
Doesn't seem fair. If there's anyone
可以拥有源源不断的伯特币  那就该是你伯特
who should never run out of Burt Bucks, it's Burt.
肯定有办法
There's got to be a way
让我们摆脱困境
we can bail ourselves out of this.
我们可不可以直接多印一些伯特币呢
What if we just print ourselves some extra Burt Bucks?
这对大家都好啊
I mean, that's good for everyone,
因为我们花得越多
because the more we spend,
别的人也能花得更多
the more everyone else will have to spend.
我不是股神巴菲特
I'm no Warren Buffet,
但我敢说
but I bet that's just the
这能刺激我们以物换物经济
thing to stimulate our bartering economy.
在别人家豪宅的厕所里干活儿时
Reading those money magazines while you're on the can
读的那些金融杂志总算有用武之地了
in the fancy houses you clean is really paying off.
我聪明绝顶*
*I've got the brains
你容貌倾城*
*And you've got the looks
我们可以大赚特赚*
*Let's make lots of money
你孔武有力*
*You've got the brawn
我思维敏捷*
*I've got the brains
我们可以大赚特赚*
*Let's make lots of
阴谋诡计交给我*
*I've had enough of scheming
混天魔王就是我*
*And messing around with jerks
豪车就在门外*
*My car is parked outside
只怕如今事与愿违*
*I'm afraid it doesn't work
我苦苦寻觅伴侣*
*I'm looking for a partner
一个无所不能的高手*
*Someone who gets things fixed
何不扪心自问*
*Ask yourself this question
你想不想发大财*
*Do you want to be rich
让我们联手  我聪明绝顶*
*Let's...I've got the brains
赚大钱  你容貌倾城*
*Make...Youe e got the looks
让我们大赚特赚*
*Let's make lots of money
让我们联手  你孔武有力*
*Let's...You've got the brawn
赚大钱  我才思敏捷*
*Make...I've got the brain
就让我们  大赚特赚*
*Let's make lots of money...
机油已经换好了
Oil change is done.
再换一次吧
Change it again!
太爽了
That was amazing.
是啊  我们在纸钱堆里大干了一场
Yeah. Now that we've made sweet love on paper money,
要用回硬币就有难度了
it's gonna be really hard to go back to coins.
简直难以置信
I can't believe this.
我在网上火了  都有58个人看过了
I'm all over the Internet. I've got 58 views,
我每看一次  点击率就增加一次
and every time I check it, it gets higher.
看啊  59个人看过了
Look at this! 59!
你看了多少遍了
How many times have you checked it?
不知道  五十次吧  还是五十五
I don't know, 50, 55.
我不想小题大做  但...
I don't want to be dramatic, about this, but...
你还不如让我死在急救课上算了
sometimes I wish you had just let me die in that first aid class.
吉米  听着
Jimmy, look...
怎么回事
What was that?
我觉得是有人进了储藏室
I think there's somebody in the garage.
是吗  在超市里的那场戏还不够吗
Really? Your little stunt in the grocery store wasn't enough?
-得了  -不是的
- Oh, come on. - No.
蒙面的歹徒  搞什么啊
A masked burglar? I mean, what... what is this,
-史酷比[卡通狗]吗  -吉米  我...
- Scooby-Doo? - Jimmy, I...
乔希
Josh?
你怎么能雇一个最爱取笑我的人
How could you hire the guy who makes the most fun of me
来让我更加无地自容
to make me feel even worse about myself?
我没雇他  他应该是真的来抢劫的
I did not hire him. I think he's actually trying to rob us.
是嘛  我真得信了
Oh, yeah, like I'm supposed to believe that this is real.
吉米
Jimmy!
怎么老发生这种事
Why does this keep happening?
你应该感到羞愧
You... should be ashamed.
你海豹突击六队的兄弟
What would your brothers at SEAL Team Six
会怎么说
have to say about this?
可能会说"乔希是谁"
Probably, "Who's Josh?"
因为我之前明显是在撒谎
Because I was obviously lying about that.
我刚从监狱出来  笨蛋
I was in prison, you idiots.
你刚从监狱出来
So you just got out of prison
就打算抢劫我们
and you're already trying to rob us?
大房子  弱娇妻  蠢老公
Big house, tiny wife, wimpy husband--
入室窃贼的理想对象啊
it's what every home invader dreams of.
太好了  现在警察和全镇人
Oh, great. Now the police and everyone in town
都要知道你又救了我一次
are gonna know that you saved me one more time.
这镇子我住不下去了
I'm never gonna be able to live this down.
吉米  就告诉大家
Jimmy, we could just tell everybody
是你救了我  行吧  谁知道啊
that you saved me, okay? Who's gonna know?
-我知道  -我也知道
- I'll know. - I'll know, too.
知道吗  给你来点胶带
You know what? Maybe a little duct tape
你就能消停
is gonna shut you up...
马上...
in about...
吉米  这是什么
Jimmy, wha... what is this?
那个啊  那个
Oh, those? Uh... that's...
什么都不是  给我
that's nothing. I'll-I'll get those.
等等  都是寄给我的  我怎么从来没见过
Wait, but these are all addressed to me-- why haven't I seen them?
可能是喜旺放在这的  你知道的
Maybe Hope put them in here-- you know that she likes
她喜欢扮邮递员  喜欢囤东西
to play mailman and hoarder.
大多是我妈寄来的明信片
It's more of those postcards from my mom.
怎么会在这
What are they doing out here?
我都会在你看到之前  就把明信片藏在这
I always, um, hide them in here before you see them,
因为我知道你看了会难过
because I know how much they upset you.
我错了
I'm sorry.
这是什么意思
What was that for?
奖励你为了让我不难过
Because you committed
而犯下的联邦罪行
a federal crime to protect my feelings.
吉米  你还不明白吗
Oh, Jimmy, don't you see?
可能我是救过你几次  但
I may have saved you a couple times, but...
你每天都在救我
you save me every day.
我想念狱中的老公了
I miss my prison husband.
-啥  -没啥
- What?  - Nothin'.
伯特  搞定
Burt, we've done it!
咱的生活水平倍儿高啊
We are livin' the good life.
虽然这三天除了龙虾  黄油和枫糖浆
And even though I haven't eaten anything but lobster,
我啥也没吃过
butter and maple syrup for the last three days,
但感觉前所未有的爽
I have never felt better.
我在想
You know, I was thinking,
龙虾确实不错
while lobster is pretty damn good,
但还有啥是追踪镇有  而纳什维尔镇没有的
what does Tracetown have that Natesville doesn't?
第三世界国家的阅读能力
Reading level of a third grade country.
不  我是说我们没有的东西  比如排骨
No, something we don't have: delicious ribs.
咱们应该扩大系统
Mmm. It's time to expand our system,
把其他镇也拉进来
bring other towns in.
这样就有更多的商品和服务
Which would mean more goods and services.
不仅有排骨
And not just ribs.
还有馅饼
We could get pies.
或者皮肤科医生
Or a dermatologist.
做钥匙的工匠
A guy who makes keys.
吉斯先生和吉斯夫人好
Hey, Chances.
泰勒  很潮嘛
Hey, Tyler. Lookin' sharp!
来杯枫糖浆吧
Pour yourself a glass of maple syrup.
不用了  问一下
Oh, I'm good. Uh, let me ask you,
你们是不是印了额外的伯特币
you didn't print up any extra Burt Bucks, did you?
我们才不会承认
We're not saying we did,
但如果我们承认  有问题吗
but if we did... why would that be a problem?
我就知道
I had a feeling.
市场货币贬值了
You flooded the market.
不用谢
You're welcome.
这不是好事  我上一个龙虾卖了4000伯特币
It's not good. I sold my last lobster for 4,000 Burt Bucks.
你们没有从
Didn't you learn anything
津巴布韦的超级通货膨胀中得到教训吗
from the hyper-inflation fiasco in Zimbabwe?
我们有自己的路子  跟津什么韦的路子不一样
We didn't do it the Zim-bob-way, we did it our way.
抱歉  两位
I'm sorry, guys,
伯特币贬值  我不收伯特币了
Burt Bucks are worthless; I can't accept them anymore.
再见
See you around.
就他一个人  不影响
Well, that's just one guy. It shouldn't matter.
系统太大了  不可能崩溃
System's too big-- it can't fail.
但不只是一个人
But it wasn't just one guy,
几个小时内整个系统就崩塌了
and it only took a couple hours for the entire system to fail.
龙虾一没了  糖浆也不行了
Once lobster was out, big syrup fell,
接着整个编织业都垮了
and then the entire crochet industry unraveled.
很快  我爹妈只能收拾这堆烂摊子
Pretty soon, my parents were left holding the bag...
这次  还有几辆堆满废纸的独轮车
or, in this case, several wheelbarrows filled with worthless paper.
如果单考虑独轮车方面
I guess if you think about this purely in terms of wheelbarrows,
我们还走在了前列
we came out way ahead.
也没人真的遭受损失
And... nobody really got hurt.
对
True.
有人吗
Hello?
有人啊
Oh, hello!
李先生  你怎么来了
Mr. Lee? What are you doing here?
管你们要印刷的钱
Well, I need to get paid for the printing.
没问题  能用伯特币吗
No problem. Can I pay you in Burt Bucks?
很幽默嘛
That's very funny!
我拿这堆假钱能干嘛使
What can I do with all the play money?
不能付房租  也不能买油墨
I can't pay rent, I can't buy ink,
当厕纸又太硬
and it's far too rough for toilet paper.
这账单你得付了
You need to take care of this.
行
Okay.
有点意思
Interesting. Mm-hmm.
劳驾问下
Let me ask you this.
独轮车能抵债吗
Do you take wheelbarrows?
爹妈的换物系统确实成真了
Mom and Dad's bartering system finally worked...
只跟他们预想的不一样
just not how they planned.
他们享受了一个星期的奢华生活
They lived the high life for one week,
但为此要做5万小时的修剪和清洗工
but it cost them 50,000 hours of landscaping and cleaning.
伯特  这边修好到楼后去
Burt, when you're done,
那边还好多树篱要修呢
there are more hedges behind the building.
真棒啊
Nice!
往好的想  这麻烦不会永远是咱的
Well, on the bright side, this won't be our problem forever.
等咱死了  咱们的孩子还有孩子的孩子
After we're gone, our children and our children's children
还要为我们给这个中国印刷工还债
will be paying off our debts to the Chinese printer.
政府由比我们聪明的人掌权
Well, it's a good thing people
真是一大幸事
smarter than us are running the real government.